The most powerful man in the world.
J. Edgar is a drama, crime, history film directed by Clint Eastwood.
As the face of law enforcement in the United States for almost 50 years, J.
Edgar Hoover was feared and admired, reviled and revered.
But behind closed doors, he held secrets that would have
destroyed his image, his career, and his life.
John Edgar Hoover, played by Leonardo DiCaprio.
Clyde Tolson, played by Armie Hammer.
Helen Gandy, played by Naomi Watts.
Charles Lindbergh, played by Josh Lucas.
Robert Irwin, played by Josh Hamilton.
Anna Marie Hoover, played by Judi Dench.
Edgar is a 2011 American biographical drama film
based on the career of FBI director J.
Edgar Hoover, directed and produced by Clint Eastwood.
Written by Dustin Lance Black, the film focuses on
Hoover's life from the 1919 Palmer Raids onward.
The film stars Leonardo DiCaprio in the title role along with Armie Hammer, Naomi Watts,
Josh Lucas, and Judi Dench, and features Adam Driver in his film debut.
Edgar opened the AFI Fest 2011 in Los Angeles on November 3, 2011, and had its limited
release on November 9, 2011, followed by wide release on November 11.
The film received mixed reviews from critics, although DiCaprio's
performance was widely praised, and it grossed $84 million worldwide.
It was chosen by the National Board of Review and American Film Institute as one of the top ten films of 2011, while DiCaprio earned a nomination for a Golden Globe
Award and both he and Hammer earned Screen Actors Guild Award nods (Hammer was nominated for Outstanding Performance by a Male Actor in a Supporting Role).
The film explores themes of fbi, biography, historical figure, lgbt, gay theme.
The tone is emotional.